lmran Abdulkadir

imranabdul22@gmail.com (920) 723-018 Gerji Addis Ababa, Addis Ababa

Summary

Highly skilled, motivated, determined and fast learner software engineer with 7 years of experience. worked on 20+ projects on several programming languages. helped to enhance productivity and transparency. helped a big government organization to minimize work time by 90%.

Education

Addis Ababa Science & Technology University

Software engineering · Addis Ababa

06/2017

finished with 3.25 and was awarded the tecno application development competition for winning 1st developing j2me software in 2016

Bahir Dar University

Economics • Addis Ababa

01/2018

finished with 2.9

Skills

- Databases
- Laravel
- JavaScript
- MySQL
- CSS3
- · Project Management

• PHP

- ReactJS
- Vue js
- HTML5
- · React Native

Experience

Vulcan Investment group

Software Project Manager • Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

08/2020 - Present

- headed and developed a marketing information management system system for Ethiopian coffee and tea authority using react js for the front end, loopback and express js for the back end and mongodb for the database.
- spearheaded and developed an extension modules for the marketing information management system for GIZ ethiopia.
- headed and developed a restaurant management system for Bellevue hotel and spa using php, ajax and JavaScript..vulcanig.net/rms
- developed HR management system using php , JavaScript and ajax..vulcanig net/hr
- developed inventory management system using Laravel and javascript

Vulcan Investment Group

Senior Software Engineer • Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

07/2016 - 08/2020

- Developed more than 13 fully customizable and responsive website
- Developed school management system using php
- Developed furniture store system using php and HTML

- Developed shopping website using WordPress and woocommerce .habzon.com
- Developed an inventory management system using php and JavaScript.. I. e vulcanig. net/stock

EMG

Contractual ICT developer · Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

10/2017 - 04/2018

Help in maintaining and configuration of server SMS portals and bulk sms softwares

Bunifu Advertisment

Web Developer • Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

01/2016 - 09/2016

Created several fully dynamic and responsive websites using HTML,CSS,Javascript,AJAX and PHP like bunifuad and dinicon

CNET Technology

Intern • Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

02/2016 - 06/2016

Helped in creating an Android app for the erp solution

Languages

English

Fluent

Amharic

• Fluent